export const chapter = "Chapter - 1: Periods and Sources";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "What is the primary purpose of studying history, according to the text?",
        optionA: "To memorize important dates",
        optionB:
          "To understand different aspects of life and their changes over time",
        optionC: "To analyze the exploits of rulers",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which of the following statements is true about the modern period in India?",
        optionA: "It started in the 15th century.",
        optionB:
          "It signifies the colonial period and the struggle for freedom.",
        optionC: "It began with Aurangzeb's birth in 1707.",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "How is the modern period in India related to the British presence?",
        optionA:
          "The British never played a significant role in the modern period.",
        optionB: "The British started to gain power during the modern period.",
        optionC:
          "The British only arrived in India after the modern period ended.",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "When did the modern period in India officially begin according to the text?",
        optionA: "15th century",
        optionB: "18th century",
        optionC: "19th century",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the purpose of government surveys mentioned in the text?",
        optionA: "To promote tourism in India",
        optionB: "To determine revenue areas for tax collection",
        optionC: "To preserve forests and wildlife",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which category of sources includes books, government records, newspaper articles, and private records?",
        optionA: "Primary Sources",
        optionB: "Secondary Sources",
        optionC: "Literary Sources",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the significance of newspapers, magazines, periodicals, and journals in studying history?",
        optionA: "They help in reconstructing fictional stories.",
        optionB:
          "They provide insight into contemporary events and perspectives.",
        optionC: "They focus on ancient history.",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Which of the following is considered an 'other source' of history?",
        optionA: "Government laws and records",
        optionB: "Diaries and letters",
        optionC: "Buildings and monuments",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "What is the importance of folk tales and songs in understanding history?",
        optionA: "They provide information about contemporary events.",
        optionB: "They are fictional and have no historical value.",
        optionC: "They have no relevance to the study of history.",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Why is it important to interpret historical sources holistically?",
        optionA: "To promote a specific ideology",
        optionB: "To ensure a one-sided view of history",
        optionC: "To understand history from multiple perspectives",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      {
        question:
          "The study of history helps us understand different aspects of life and how they __________ over time.",
        optionA: "remained constant",
        optionB: "changed",
        optionC: "disappeared",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The modern period in India, also known as the colonial period, began in the __________ century when the British gained power.",
        optionA: "15th",
        optionB: "18th",
        optionC: "19th",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British conducted surveys to determine revenue areas where they could impose __________ on land.",
        optionA: "taxes",
        optionB: "regulations",
        optionC: "restrictions",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Private records, such as diaries, travelogues, and letters, have often helped discover historical occurrences quite __________.",
        optionA: "inaccurately",
        optionB: "vividly",
        optionC: "correctly",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Buildings and monuments, like the Rashtrapati Bhavan and India Gate, are important sources of history that have been constructed during the __________ period.",
        optionA: "ancient",
        optionB: "medieval",
        optionC: "modern",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Folk traditions, including folk tales and songs, have preserved many historical occurrences and events over __________.",
        optionA: "generations",
        optionB: "centuries",
        optionC: "decades",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The modern period in India began in the 18th century, which is often considered from the year of __________ death, Aurangzeb.",
        optionA: "Akbar's",
        optionB: "Shah Jahan's",
        optionC: "Aurangzeb's",
        correctAnswer: "C",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British exploited the river valley farmers by compelling them to produce crops like __________ for their trade.",
        optionA: "wheat",
        optionB: "indigo",
        optionC: "rice",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Primary sources, such as government surveys, buildings, and archaeological remains, directly indicate different historical __________.",
        optionA: "events",
        optionB: "interpretations",
        optionC: "ideologies",
        correctAnswer: "A",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British published gazettes that included not only surveys but also records of events, providing insight into various aspects of contemporary __________.",
        optionA: "politics",
        optionB: "life",
        optionC: "culture",
        correctAnswer: "B",
      },
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Metal is a recyclable waste.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The modern period in India is also known as the colonial period.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Private records, such as diaries and letters, have little historical value.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Folk traditions, including folk tales and songs, have preserved historical occurrences over generations.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The British exploited river valley farmers by compelling them to produce crops like rice.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Buildings and monuments like the Rashtrapati Bhavan have no significance in studying history.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The modern period in India officially began in the 15th century.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Government surveys and records are considered secondary sources of history.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
      {
        question:
          "Newspapers, magazines, and journals are not important sources of historical information.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "True",
      },
      {
        question:
          "The study of history is primarily focused on analyzing the exploits of rulers.",
        optionA: "True",
        optionB: "False",
        correctAnswer: "False",
      },
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
